<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Resume>
    <Person>
        <Name>HOUDAIFA Youness</Name>
        <Title>Java Spring Boot Developer</Title>
        <Experience>3 years of experience</Experience>
        <Image src="images/image2.jpg"/>
        <Address>
            <Street>120 Paul Doumer Street</Street>
            <City>Loos</City>
            <Country>France</Country>
        </Address>
        <Email>unes.houdaifa@gmail.com</Email>
        <Phone>+33 6 70 62 73 81</Phone>
        <Description>Java developer, specialized in N-Tier solutions design. With experience in diverse environments, including web development. I leverage my technical skills to meet business needs and ensure customer satisfaction.</Description>
    </Person>
    <Skills>
        <Skill type="Programming Languages">Java 16, JavaScript, C, Python</Skill>
        <Skill type="Web Technologies">HTML, JS, CSS (SASS), Webpack, Vite, ES, Kibana</Skill>
        <Skill type="Databases">MongoDB, MySQL, SQL Server, FireBase, PocketBase, GraphQL, Redis, Prisma</Skill>
        <Skill type="Tools and Environments">Linux, Github Action, Docker, Ansible, Jenkins, Postman</Skill>
        <Skill type="Cloud">Kubernetes Lens, k9s</Skill>
        <Skill type="Message Handling">MQTT, MQTT Explorer (Conduktor)</Skill>
        <Skill type="Collaboration Tools">Jira, Slack, Mattermost, Teams, OneNote</Skill>
        <Skill type="Frameworks and Libraries">ExpressJs, React/NextJs, Angular Svelte/Svelte Kit, SpringBoot 2, JUnit, Flutter</Skill>
        <Skill type="Work Methodologies">Agile (Scrum), UML, Merise, Relational Database Design</Skill>
        <Skill type="Development Practices">Design patterns, refactoring, modular programming, reusable and scalable classes</Skill>
        <Skill type="Testing">Unit tests, integration tests, functional tests</Skill>
        <Skill type="GitHub Profile">https://github.com/YHDF</Skill>
    </Skills>
    <Experience>
        <Job>
            <Duration>2 years (2021 - 2023)</Duration>
            <Position>Java Developer, Spring Boot</Position>
            <Company>Worldline</Company>
            <Description>
                Collaborated within an Agile Squad of 5 members for the development of the "Santé des Armées" application as part of a project to create a digital healthcare platform exclusively for the French Army;
                Responsible for setting up Build and Run operations using Spring Boot 2 (Java 11) and Angular 9 to ensure a robust and scalable architecture;
                Implemented unit and integration tests using JUnit 5 and Mockito 5 to ensure code quality, contributing to a significant increase in test coverage for the application;
                Actively contributed to continuous integration and deployment with Gitlab CI, Kubernetes, and Ansible on a private cloud, facilitating rapid and reliable application delivery;
                Close coordination of efforts within the team, especially with functional leads and project managers, through daily and weekly meetings to ensure project deadlines and budgets are met;
                Adopted agile methodology to optimize team efficiency, reduce delays, improve code quality, and ensure regular delivery, increased application stability, and high user satisfaction;
                Implemented advanced authentication mechanisms, including the use of PKI cards for secure user identification and access to sensitive medical data.
            </Description>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Duration>6 months (2021)</Duration>
            <Position>Software Development Intern</Position>
            <Company>Lutexia</Company>
            <Description>
                Worked independently on the development of a full-stack application for managing the accounting calendar and client portfolio;
                Used Node.js 14 and React 17 for development, as well as Shell Scripting for deployment;
                Implemented security measures to protect accounting and client portfolio data, including the application of security protocols (HTTPS) and management of security headers.
            </Description>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Duration>3 months (2020)</Duration>
            <Position>Web Development Intern</Position>
            <Company>Bolloré Transport and Logistics</Company>
            <Description>
                Contributed to the maintenance of a logistics control application for goods;
                Implemented alert and notification systems for potential delays, stockouts, or other logistics issues;
                Used technologies such as Express 4, React 16, and MongoDB to ensure smooth operations and an optimal user experience;
                Contributed to the implementation of security measures, including protection of cargo tracking data and access rights management to ensure data integrity.
            </Description>
        </Job>
        <Job>
            <Duration>2 months (2019)</Duration>
            <Position>Web Development Intern</Position>
            <Company>ENSA B., Morocco</Company>
            <Description>
                Participated in the development of a digital space for students;
                Used the C# 3.1 and ASP.NET 4 stack for the backend, HTML and CSS for the frontend, and SQL Server for the database;
                Responsible for implementing a session-based authentication system to ensure secure access to application features;
                Played a key role in creating web services and integrating APIs to enhance the user experience.
            </Description>
        </Job>
        <!-- Other jobs here -->
    </Experience>
    <Education>
        <Degree>
            <Duration>2021-2023</Duration>
            <Program>Master's in Application and Software Engineering</Program>
            <Institution>EFFICOM - Lille</Institution>
        </Degree>
        <Degree>
            <Duration>2020-2021</Duration>
            <Program>Bachelor's in Computer Science L3</Program>
            <Institution>University of Picardie Jules Vernes - Amiens</Institution>
        </Degree>
        <Degree>
            <Duration>2018-2020</Duration>
            <Program>University Diploma in Computer Engineering</Program>
            <Institution>ENSA B. - Morocco</Institution>
        </Degree>
        <!-- Other degrees here -->
    </Education>
    <Miscellaneous>
        <Item>
            <Title>Technological Watch</Title>
            <Description>On new Java and JavaScript libraries, as well as other technical and organizational developments in IT.</Description>
        </Item>
        <Item>
            <Title>Sports</Title>
            <Description>Regular practice of sports activities for physical and mental well-being.</Description>
        </Item>
        <Item>
            <Title>Video Games</Title>
            <Description>Video game hobby, providing relaxation and entertainment.</Description>
        </Item>
        <Item>
            <Title>Travel</Title>
            <Description>Occasional exploration of new cultures and broadening horizons through travel.</Description>
        </Item>
    </Miscellaneous>
</Resume>
